



Litvyak Ivan

Male, 52 years, born on 18 October 1968

+7 (985) 1811088

ivan.litviak@gmail.com — preferred means of communication

Reside in: Moscow

Citizenship: Russia, Ukraine, work permit at: Russia, Ukraine

Ready to relocate, ready for rare business trips

Desired position and salary

GM, Director, CEO, Quality Director, CI & Training Manager

Manufacturing, agriculture

- Pharmaceutical Industry
 - Quality Control
 - Purchasing and Supply

Employment: full time Work schedule: full day

Desired travel time to work: less than hour

Work experience — 25 years 2 months

September 2020 — till now 1 year 1 month

BOMI Group Russia

Moscow

Medicine, Pharmaceuticals, Pharmacies

• Pharmaceutical Products (Production)

Transportation, Logistics, Warehousing, International Logistics

• Warehouse Services

QA / RA manager

Development and implementation of the QMS as per ISO 9001 & ISO 13485 (medical devices) requirements for 3PL provide to the healthcare industry. Set up, implementation and certification of the QMS, set up of the Customers' Complaints monitoring and response system, Client and Suppliers audits preparation and delivery; implementing CAPA practices into SOPs and daily operation.

March 2019 — February 2020 1 year

Aircompany "Pobeda", Aeroflot group

Director Quality

In charge of all issues of Quality, Certification, business processes formulation and optimisation. Development and implementation of the business processes for further multiplication at the stage of the exponential company growth.

February 2017 — March 2019 2 years 2 months

"Ural Plant for Special Fittings building" Ltd (OMK – United Metallurgical Company group)

Director Quality

"Ural Plant for Special Fittings building" Ltd (OMK - United Metallurgical Company group) Quality Director (OMK group legal entity for machinery building for O&G sector)

- Development and implementation of the Company's management systems as per ISO 9001, 14001, OHSAS 18000;
- Development of processes covering operational activity of the Organisation (in interaction with all structural units);
- Development and implementation of the Quality Control, Metrology, Standardisation & Certification

department;

- Products manufactured certification process (incl. GasProm);
- Establishing processed for suppliers' selection and assesment, criteria of their approval;
- · Managing team of 25 permanent staff;

March 2015 — August 2016 1 year 6 months

Bureau Veritas Group, Bureau Veritas Certification Russia

Bureau Veritas Certification Director

Bureau Veritas is French Group of Companies leading in the TIC (Testing, Inspection and Certification) sector.

- Lead the certification and training in the area of the Management Systems; certification and training delivery as per ISO (ISO 9001, 14001, 22000, FSMS, OHSAS 18000, GxP and other international and corporate standards assessment and certification) at regional network of 10+ affiliates for network of abt 3000 local and international clients;
- Managing team of 100 permanent staff and 200 freelance (thru direct reporting to me Operation, Technical and Sales managers); reporting to Country Chief Executive;
- Performing overall financial management: preparing the budgets and forecasts; full P&L responsibilities;
- Implementation of the costs control of operations, development of the pricing tool for per-project's profitability calculation; dissemination of this tool to be used by all teams involved in the projects' execution that leads to 20% increase of operation profitability level;
- Development and restructuring of the regional network of sales representatives / business developers acquisition of 100+ new Clients;
- Optimisation of the operational business model to decrease the costs of operation with implementation of the quality control over the services provided by product team leaders;
- Realisation of projects on suppliers, vendors and co-packers assessment and technological assessment of their manufacturing facilities;
- Development of the service sector for Food, Pharmaceutical sector manufacturers and supply chains.

July 2014 — March 2015 9 months

International and local projects, Russia

Russia

Projects Director

Participation in several projects providing consulting at time of implementation of the new Management System and evaluation and assessment of the existing ones.

Projects Director and consultant

- Run projects at industrial and food sectors for implementation and development of the management systems and food safety management systems;
- The projects involved from 10 50 personnel with active interaction of the employees from the Companies of the projects implementation;

December 2011 — June 2014 2 years 7 months

TUV INTERNATIONAL RUS

Managing Director

German Group of companies TUV Rheinland AG providing services in inspection, testing, certification and verification of materials, equipment, processes and management systems

Managing Director, Russia and Kazakhstan

* Run 4 Business Units: Management Systems Certification (ISO 9001, 14001, 16949, 22000, FSSC, HACCP and other certification), Products Certification (E&E certification, medical devices, storage equipment GS certifications, construction materials and other products' certifications), Industrial Services (pressure vessels, steel materials, lifting equipment and devices, safety certifications) Training and Consultancy with 6 regional affiliates serving 800 local and international clients. The client list includes

between others: Siemens, Knauf, Nissan Manufacturing, Porsche, VSMPO Avisma, Lukoil, ChTPZ; BashNeft, Marusia Motors.

- * Manage a team of 50 permanent staff and 200 freelance.
- * Have restructured the Company and reached 10 25 % sales volume increase;
- * Established the Objectives Settings program, monitored the implementation, control and achievement of the Objectives in order to meet financial plans for every business unit and for the whole Company;
- * Perform overall financial management: prepared the budget and forecasts;
- * Introduced the costs control of operations, per project's profitability calculation (40% margin); determined and implemented necessary corrective and preventive actions;
- * Established the system of cooperation with international colleagues in the highly distributed matrix organisation (teams of 6 EVPs for business directions and CROs of 7 regions + standing alone German operation);
- * Represent Company towards local institutions, organisation and authorities, ensured full compliance to the Head Office requirements, Company policies and procedures and to local applicable laws and regulations; Public Relations management in changing environment;
- * Perform overall management of the human resources: implemented processes of hiring, training and developing of highly-motivated employees to support business growth and new commercial requirements, building of efficient and effective teams (70% of company personnel replaced);
- * Implemented the international corporate reporting system (SAP based) with integration to the local accounting (1C based);

July 2012 — August 2013 1 year 2 months

TUV Rheinland Ukraine

interim Managing Director

TUV Rheinland Ukraine in July 2012- August 2013: stabilised business activities, set up of new affiliate structure, supported the existing Clients network, increased numbers of new Clients.

* Lead, organised and supported business units for business development and growth, opened new service activities for new and existing Clients (3 fully new activities implemented);

September 2004 — December 2011 7 years 4 months

Group of Companies SGS SA

Business Manager of Industrial Services department and Automotive department

SGS - Swiss public Group of Companies SGS SA provides inspection, testing, certification and verification services.

Reported to Managing Director. Managed a team of 15.

- * Started Industrial Services business from scratch and reached 20% annual growth;
- * Launched Automotive department providing inspection services in to the Automotive industries
- * Started the activities of verification, testing, certification and inspection business in the Industrial sectors; product certification to the requirements of the international and national standards, of the EU directives; inspection monitoring of different construction / modernisation projects including warehousing;
- * Led the projects: EBRD project "Dnepropetrovsk Metro Expansion -Feasibility Study", "Lifting Devices certification and approval at New Shelter "NovArka", construction" and other;
- * Developed and fulfill the manufacturers' and suppliers' assessment / auditing projects; risks assessment projects;

October 1996 — September 2004 8 years

Group of Companies SGS SA

Manager of Quality and Improvement Division

SGS - Swiss public Group of Companies SGS SA provides inspection, testing, certification and verification services.

Reported to Managing Director. Managed a team of 7

- * Started and developed the business line of Management Systems (ISO 9001, 14001, 18000, 22000, 16949 and other) certification activities of foreign and local companies. Designed and implement the quality management system for SGS Ukraine, developed its general structure and procedures; set-up of the on-line service for business service Minerals:
- * Audited the Quality Management Systems of the Client's companies. Designed the different certification, quality and hazard analyses related training courses and provided them to the companies in food, construction, transportation and other industrial sectors. Registered Lead Auditor of IRCA (International Register of Certified Auditors at IQA Institute of Quality Assurance, London);
- * 3rd party Lead Auditor in the Global SGS service to food producers on certification and auditing (HACCP, FSSC, SQF, other Food Safety systems, GMP) of the affiliated / bottling companies in the Central and Eastern Europe & Middle East. Conducted audit of 15 affiliates/plants of beverages manufacturing company in the EEME region.
- * Development and providing the different trainings on Food Safety (HACCP based), Quality Aspects, Lean management, implementation of best practices (GxP) at food chains, in food manufacturing and other industrial sectors (machinery building, oil & gas, pharmaceutical, and other).

Regional Branch Manager

Reported to Managing Director. Managed a team of 20.

- * Developed and managed five Business Units in Kiev and Kiev Area, including Agricultural, Minerals, Oil, Gas and Chemical, Systems and Services Certification;
- * Ensured provision of SGS services to local and international clients.
- * Performed local management of the EU TACIS project ``Harmonization of standardization and certification in Ukraine", close co-operation with State committee for standardization, certification and metrology, standardization Department of Agricultural Ministry of Ukraine. Work with EU and Ukrainian legislation and regulations in the fields of certification, standardization and metrology.;

September 1995 — October 1996 1 year 2 months

Group of Companies SGS SA

Agricultural Division Manager Assistant

SGS - Swiss public Group of Companies SGS SA provides inspection, testing, certification and verification services.

- * Gained experience in international trade structure, performing and organization of grain and food inspection.
- * Management of inspections at inland silos for local and international clients.
- * Participated in the local management of TACIS project ``Standardization and certification in Russia and Ukraine". Involved into inductive HACCP training of few producers of milk products in Ukraine.
- * Development and implementation of the Quality Management System for Agricultural Inspections within the regional branches and laboratories of SGS Ukraine, including lean management system;

Education

Higher

2008 STEINBEIS UNIVERSITY BERLIN

International Business Relations, Master of Business Administration

2003 ODESSA STATE ACADEMY of Food Technoligies

Food technologies and processing, Master of Science

1992 ODESSA STATE UNIVERSITY

Roman & German Philology, Master of Science

Key skills

Languages Russian — Native

English — C2 — Proficiency Italian — A1 — Basic

German — A1 — Basic

Ukrainian — C2 — Proficiency French — C2 — Proficiency

Skills Работоспособность Управление качеством Управление проектами

Оптимизация бизнес-процессов Управление персоналом Обучение персонала

Технический контроль производства Leadership Skills

GMP (Good Manufacturing Practice) Suppliers Assessment Audit

Driving experience

Driver's license category B

Further information

About me

Team Management, ISO 900X Standard, overall management, overall financial management, Food Safety, HACCP, SAP, Pressure Vessel, Medical Devices, International trade, Forecasting, Feasibility Studies, Building materials, Audit, Inspection and Assessment

Responses

Менеджер по качеству поставщиков

20 September 2021

Quality Manager (Moscow)

18 October 2016

Personal Assistant

17 June 2016

Quality Assurance Specialist

8 January 2015

Quality Manager CIS (food industry)

27 December 2014

Quality Control Manager/Team Leader

24 November 2014

Country Quality Control Manager

19 November 2014

Country Quality Control Manager

28 October 2014

Country Quality Control Manager

14 October 2014